I know I see everybody today we're going
to talk about api's this video is one of
the first videos of the series called
new big questions let's get started what
is an API why so many people talk about
API so why are they so important why
does everybody have an API what is a
Facebook API Instagram API an API is
just basically like this keyboard light
right here with this keyword we interact
with a computer when I press a button
here beautiful button that I can press
something happens inside of this
something happens inside of my computer
and that showed me the text on the
screen all right
I'm interacting with the computer
through the keyboard that's how I am
inputting information with the keys that
they have provided this is the only way
I can interact with my computer now an
API is something like this an API is how
do programs interact with each other an
API is made for code to be able to
interact with basically other code or
other technology an API is just
basically this keyword that you make
from your server and you give that
keyword to the iOS application boom with
this key you're going to login with this
key you're going to log out with this
key you're going to upload a photo with
this key you're going to follow somebody
and when the iOS or Android presses
these keys that is going to have an
effect on the database back there on
your servers far away that is basically
an API now what is a REST API what is a
graph to the API what is a soap API what
is an XML API these are just different
shapes of keyboards but they accomplish
the same thing
they let programs communicate with each
other but this is not the only API that
you can find you can also find public
API so there is weathers a weather API
which is a server that has the weather
of everywhere in the world and when you
press the button get weather of Korea is
going to show you that weather also we
have Instagram API we have Facebook APs
those are just keyboards that your
program can use to interact we
those applications with those servers
now api's are designed by the people
that have the server and that are making
the API so for example some api's they
don't allow you to do everything
sometimes the API is come with
limitations sometimes you have to pay
for access to the key word sometimes you
can only send maybe ten requests per
second there is another kind of API
which is for example the Web API where
api's our API is made for the browser
for Google Chrome for Firefox for all
that and those are the same thing they
the chrome team the Firefox team the
Safari team they all exposed buttons for
you to use every time there is a new
button popping up and before the API was
really really small like this is Moe
only this part was the API but now it's
being growing so now we have buttons for
example that if I press this button I
can request access to the user
microphone if I play if I press this
button I can also request access to the
user camera
if I press another button I request
access to the geolocation so those are
all just buttons that you press to have
some result you don't see the internals
of that job you don't see the internals
of how Chrome is getting my location you
don't see the internals of how Firefox
is getting my audio you don't do any of
that they just give you a button and
when you press it many things happen
under it but that's not your problem and
that's why everybody loves an API they
have different purposes but they do the
same thing they just expose buttons that
then you can press with your code and
that will have some result at the end so
do you need an API you don't need an API
it'll depends on your needs should you
build an API 11-hour it depends on your
needs should you learn how to make an
API of course you should you can learn
that in our courses or everywhere in the
world thank you for watching I hope that
you liked this tiny tiny explanation let
me know what other new big questions you
have I would love to answer them on the
comments or on another video and that's
it again thank you and I will see you on
the next one don't forget as always
80 mg